

Durgesh Kumar



+91-8090123604



durgeshyadavalld@gmail.com



Noida, U.P., India, 201014

Social Links

- **Linkedin**
- **HackerRank**
- <u>GitHub</u>

Skills Highlights

- Java
- **Spring Boot**
- Git
- **Tomcat Server**
- **Swagger**
- **Rest Api**
- Html/CSS
- **Bootstrap**
- **JPA**

Language

- **English**
- Hindi

Hobbies

- Writing
- Cricket
- **Traveling**
- Reading

Profile

I have total 2-year experience as a Java Developer. I have demonstrated a strong understanding of various technologies, particularly Spring MVC, Spring Boot. I am able to grasp complex concepts and apply them effectively in my projects.

Project Experience

- Developed and maintained a secure Banking System using Java.
- Led the implementation of a user-friendly Hospital Management System using Java JSP and MySQL.
- Designed and developed an efficient Attendance Management System using Java and MySQL.
- Worked on the Dashboard and Recommendation Engine of Zee5 at Zee Entertainment Enterprises Limited, utilizing Spring Boot and Docker.
- Developed Bpm-Core software with 5 panels and distinct responsibilities, involving Rest-Api design, coding, and deployment. Utilized Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL, and JPA.

Technical Skills

- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Micronaut, Apache Tomcat Server.
- Software: Postman, Git, Swagger-UI, Docker.
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, H2.

Experience

Software Developer Grater Noida

Uway Software Solution Jul 2023 - Present

- Developed and maintained secure Banking System in Java.
- Led implementation of user-friendly Hospital Management System (Java JSP,
- Designed efficient Attendance Management System (Java, MySQL).
- Resolved complex technical issues and optimized performance.
- Implemented continuous integration and delivery practices.
- Mentored junior developers and facilitated collaboration.

Software Developer Ventur7

Faridabad Feb 2022-Jun 2022

Created multiple reports and document as per requirement for development.

Stayed updated with industry trends and recommended innovations.

Work on the health Management System, using .Net,HTML,CSS and Bootstrap.

BlueThink Inc. Java Developer Noida Nov 2022 - Jul 2023

- Hands on experience of CRUD operations on Spring MVC, Spring Boot and Micronut framework.
- Developed a Java-based web application with an intuitive UI that increased engagement of users.
- Developed a REST API that enabled integration with third-party services, resulting in an increase in customer retention.
- Designed and implemented a secure user authentication system.
- Oaths for user authorization and authentication. Developed a RESTful API that handled as per requests per day with response times.

Education

Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science and Engineering)

Krishna Engineering college Ghaziabad

CGPA: 7.2 2018 -2022